[
    {
        "Answer": "The counsellor is available on the campus on Tuesdays at 4:30 PM and the psychiatrist is available on Wednesdays at 4:30 PM.",
        "Category": [
            "Student Counselling Programme",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "91",
        "Question": "What is the timing in which the psychiatrist and the counselor are available on the campus ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Both remedial and bridge classes serve the same purpose of helping a student to have a better understanding of a subject and perform better in exams. Only difference between them is that bridge classes are for foreign students whereas remedial classes are for all others.",
        "Category": [
            "Student Counselling Programme"
        ],
        "QNO": "90",
        "Question": "How are remedial classes different from bridge classes ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Both remedial and bridge classes serve the same purpose of helping a student to have a better understanding of a subject and perform better in exams. Only difference between them is that bridge classes are for foreign students whereas remedial classes are for all others.",
        "Category": [
            "Student Counselling Programme"
        ],
        "QNO": "89",
        "Question": "How are remedial classes different from bridge classes ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "4 societies - technical, arts and cultural, sports, literary \r\nEach with 4 elected (1 each from 2nd,3rd,4th and PG) and 1 nominated secretary dean/director nominee.\r\n3*2conveners elected for each fest and one nominated convenor\r\nThe secretaries function under VPs of respective societies.\r\nThere are satellite club under each society.\r\nhttps://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2018/04/09/1812-sac-restructuring-changed-for-the-better/\r\nhttps://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/info/sac-info/",
        "Category": [
            "Student Activity Centre"
        ],
        "QNO": "88",
        "Question": "SAC structure ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Innovision - the techno management fest \r\nCosmopolitan - multiethnic cultural festival\r\nInnovation carnival - the enterprenurship festival\r\nVriddhi - sports fest\r\nNITRUtsav - cultural fest\r\nRoots - creative confluence of NITR\r\nTechX - all tech devoted fest",
        "Category": [
            "Student Activity Centre"
        ],
        "QNO": "87",
        "Question": "Various fest in the institute ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "One scholarship is endowed by the Pendayala Anusaya Memorial. The monetary aid given in ₹40,000 (Citation required, couldn't be confirmed by anyone). Meritorious girl students from chemical, biotechnology or biomedical branch are eligible for this. The students are selected on the basis of their first year performance. The student should secure a minimum CGPA of 8.5 after first year and maintain consistency in her performance with a minimum CGPA of 8.0 till graduation. In case her CGPA drops below 8.0, she will have to forfeit the scholarship and the scholarship will be awarded to a student in third semester through fresh selection.\r\n\r\nnitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/FacultyStaff/docs/181501331055_1.pdf",
        "Category": [
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "86",
        "Question": "What are the different scholarships endowed by the Pendayala Anasuya Memorial? What is the monetary aid given? Who are eligible for this? What are the different eligible criterions for the same? Where does one submit the application form ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "All the Scholarships by major state governments are listed below. The eligibility criteria and procedure to apply can be found out from the attached links.\r\n\r\n\r\n1. Kerala\r\nE-grantz scholarship\r\nwww.e-grantz.kerala.gov.in\r\n\r\n2. Tamil Nadu\r\nAdi Dravidar Welfare Development Scholarship\r\nwww.tn.gov.in\r\n\r\n3. West Bengal\r\nBackward Classes Welfare Directorate Scholarship\r\nwww.oasis.gov.in\r\n\r\n4. Madhya Pradesh\r\nDirectorate of Scheduled Castes Development Scholarship\r\nhttps://scdd.kerala.gov.in\r\n\r\n5. Odisha\r\nPRERANA Scholarship\r\nwww.mpsc.mp.nic.in › scholarships\r\n\r\n6. Chattisgarh\r\nDirectorate of SC-ST development Scholarship\r\nmpsc.mp.nic.in › cgpms\r\n\r\n7. Jammu and Kashmir -\r\n AICTE https://mhrd.gov.in/sites/upload_files/mhrd/files/upload_document/Guidelines_SSS_JK2018-19.pdf&ved=2ahUKEwj58cLorurgAhUMMY8KHVAKCLUQFjAAegQIAhAB&usg=AOvVaw1rZ_o6tDnz4I2Si9vBb7wg and https://mhrd.gov.in/sites/upload_files/mhrd/files/upload_document/Guidelines_SSS_JK2018-19.pdf\r\n\r\n8. Delhi - \r\nPost Matric Scholarship for ST/SC - http://scstwelfare.delhigovt.nic.in/&ved=2ahUKEwihtZ31s-rgAhUKuI8KHXl8BUUQFjACegQIBRAB&usg=AOvVaw142l3ny-A076iEvO5ECUam\r\n\r\n9.Gujarat - \r\nPost Matric Scholarship for ST SC - https://www.digitalgujarat.gov.in/loginapp/CitizenLogin.aspx\r\n\r\n10.Haryana - \r\nPost Matric Scholarship - http://techeduhry.gov.in/sc-scholarships\r\n\r\n11. Rajasthan -\r\n Social Justice and empowerment - http://www.sje.rajasthan.gov.in/Default.aspx?PageID=346\r\n\r\n12. Assam, Chandigarh, Bihar, Uttarakhand, Tripura, Karnataka, Meghalaya, Arunachal Pradesh - \r\nNational Scholarship Portal - https://scholarships.gov.in\r\n\r\n13. Andhra Pradesh -\r\n Epass Scholarship-  https://epass.apcfss.in/\r\n\r\n14. Telangana -\r\n Epass Scholarship https://telanganaepass.cgg.gov.in/\r\n\r\n15. Punjab - \r\nDr. Ambedkar Scholarship - http://punjabscholarships.gov.in\r\n\r\n16. Uttar Pradesh -\r\n Saksham Scholarship - http://scholarship.up.nic.in/index.aspx\r\n\r\n17. Himachal Pradesh\r\nEpass\r\nhttps://hpepass.cgg.gov.in/NewHomePage.do\r\n\r\n18. Maharashtra - \r\nPost Matric Scholarship - https://mahadbtmahait.gov.in\r\n\r\n19. Jharkhand\r\nE-Kalyan\r\nhttps://ekalyan.cgg.gov.in",
        "Category": [
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "85",
        "Question": "What are the various scholarships for SC/ST run by various state governments? Please mention the eligibility criteria and procedure to apply for the same ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "NSP is national scholarship programme of goi\r\nDetails are present here\r\nhttps://scholarships.gov.in/#",
        "Category": [
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "84",
        "Question": "NSP ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "One needs to have cleared the NTSE examination in class X to be eligible for the NTSE scholarship.\r\nThe scholarship amount will be disbursed as soon as the student gets promoted to class XI. Further details regarding the scholarship can be found in the link given below:\r\n\r\nhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1L-u1FAb0rkvl15Rrc4vRo8ulQbRWGQA-/view?usp=drivesdk\r\n\r\na)\tScholarship of Rs. 1250/ per Months for class XI and XII .\r\nb)\tScholarship of Rs. 2000/ per month for Under Graduates and Post Graduates.\r\n\r\nIn order to get the scholarship amount every year during college life , every undergraduate needs to upload all the necessary filled NTSE claim bill forms along with signed transcript on the NTSE website.",
        "Category": [
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "83",
        "Question": "Please furnish details about the NTSE Scholarship ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The guest house can be booked through any faculty member who will book a room. A student can directly call his /her faculty advisor to book the room.",
        "Category": [
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "82",
        "Question": "Book a guest house ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The person should ideally approach his guide, and if the issue isn’t still solve, then the editorial board and peer reviewers.\r\nDue to the question being PhD related, it was a little out of our scope to get information on a recent case in the given time period.",
        "Category": [
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "81",
        "Question": "Who can give justice in issues of research misconduct such as denial ofauthorship? Which committee is there to address issues of publication practices and responsible authorship? Has anyone reported such type of case? If yes how It has been solved ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The procedure is to go to Warden and then the Chief Warden. There has been a recent case where a committee was made to confirm the same.",
        "Category": [
            "Halls",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "80",
        "Question": "What is the procedure to be taken up for complaining against the decreasingquality of mess food ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "When student is on official leave from the institute, for eg: when sport teams go for sport fests and tournaments elsewhere, similarly applying for the dance clubs, etc. \r\nIn this case, the student must talk to the warden and submit an application to the Cheif Warden. There won’t be a refund. Students will have to pay less in the next semester, subtracting the amount of refund they are expecting and this value comes under mess dues. All meals of a day in the mess cost a total of 93 rupees.",
        "Category": [
            "Halls",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "79",
        "Question": "Under what circumstances can the Mess Leave option be availed by thestudents? When does one expect a refund ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A psychiatrist is a physician who sprcializes in psychiatry, a bunch of medicine devoted to the diagnosis, prevention, study and treatment of disorder.\r\nWhere a counsellor is a trained to give guidance on personal or psychological problem. He/she could be an advisor, consultant, guide, mentor etc.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Student Counselling Programme",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "78",
        "Question": "How are the roles of a psychiatrist and a counselor different ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Software vault is the official software hub of nit Rourkela. It provides licensed software to students. So that students won’t face troubles while installing any software’s, it comes with product keys etc. link: http://192.168.1.126/ ",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "77",
        "Question": "What is the software vault for NIT Rourkela? How is it useful for students?What is the link to the same ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "All the complaints about the prices of items being sold inside NITR can be done to OCB (On Campus Business) Committee. Complaints along with proof can be sent to following mail ids of the members of OCB committee. kcb@nitrkl.ac.in;hbsahu@nitrkl.ac.in; hmjena@nitrkl.ac.in; dillip@nitrkl.ac.in; fcchhatoi@nitrkl.ac.in; purchase@nitrkl.ac.in; 514id1004@nitrkl.ac.in.\r\n\r\nhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1H3EZT5sAOIDmyC3csthLhfxB6_00pxT4/view?usp=drivesdk",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "76",
        "Question": "Where does one complain about the price of items being sold at general stores in NIT Rourkela ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The schedule for physical education can be found on the notice boards of G.D.B. Hall of residence/M.V. Hall of residence / K.M.S. Hall of Residence/ C.V.R. Hall of Residence / SAC/Gym. / Institute. ",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "75",
        "Question": "Where can one find the list of dates for various Physical Education Classes ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Adding to the previous answer, the Internal Complaints Committee has jurisdiction in such matters on behalf of the college.",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "74",
        "Question": "Who can give justice in issues of research misconduct such as denial ofauthorship? Which committee is there to address issues of publication practices and responsible authorship? Has anyone reported such type of case? If yes how It has been solved ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Passport camps are not held inside the campus. \r\n\r\nOne has to apply for a passport online first following which he/she has to report at the (only) passport camp in Rourkela for verification of documents.",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "73",
        "Question": "Are passport camps held in the institute? How can one apply for a passport atNIT, is there any such procedure for it ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "No. \r\nThe Director intends to get it done so, that all NITR students can avail this concession asap.\r\nThe proposal is still in the process of getting sanctioned by Senate.",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "72",
        "Question": "Do the students of NIT Rourkela get some concession while booking ticketswith the Indian Railways ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The Estate Office, situated beside KMS Hall of Residence is responsible for all the non-academic standard of living matters on-campus such as that of renovating or reparatory works in halls, managing the electricity, managing the tendering for the working staff of halls, lab infrastructure, etc. \r\n",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "71",
        "Question": "What is the role of the estate office on campus ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "5:15-6:00 pm\r\n6:00-6-40 pm\r\n7:30-8:10 pm\r\nWeekdays\r\n\r\n8:15-9:00 am\r\n9:00-9-40 am\r\n+ the above\r\nWeekends\r\n\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "70",
        "Question": "Swimming pool and central Gymnasium timings ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "If a student has already paid the whole semester fee for a semester but wishes to have a free waiver by showing income certificate later. It is allowed. First the students’ needs to provide the income certificate to the dean of academics and talk with the registrar.",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "69",
        "Question": "If a student has already paid the whole fee for a semester but wishes to have afee waiver by showing his income certificate later? Is this allowed? If yes, what is theprocedure to do so ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The document can be found at www.nitrkl.ac.in/docs/Misc/CommunicationHandBook.pdf but it isn't the upadted Version. So one should refer faculty directory at http://www.nitrkl.ac.in/FacultyStaff/EmployeeDirectory/Faculty.aspx",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "68",
        "Question": "Where can one find the official document of the institute for contacting authorities across departments ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Various punishments include -\r\n\r\n-Award of ‘UR’ status to all courses of current semesters that is repeat of wholeyear. \r\n-Year Back.\r\n-Conversionof grades to ‘UR’ status in three courses in his current semester and instructhim to go for slow pace.\r\n-Awardof ‘UR’ status to all the courses of current semester that is forcing forrepeat of semester.\r\n-Reductionof grades by one in all the courses in current semester of the program.\r\n-Delaying publication of final result by 3 months, degree may be given in the same ornext year depending on  the date ofconvocation.\r\n-Reductionof grades in two courses (having highest grades) by one in the current  semester.\r\n\r\nBut punishments are at times subjective depending upon the specificity and situation of the particular case\r\n\r\nhttp://www.nitrkl.ac.in/docs/AcademicRegulation/08032017102846436.pdf",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "67",
        "Question": "What are the various punishments awarded for ragging ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "https://www.ftbi-nitrkl.org/join-ftbi\r\n\r\nProcedure guideline document for admission to FTBI here:\r\nhttps://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/192ce1_02ffafbe4a47439387d91d5d433201cb.docx?dn=Admission%20to%20FTBI%20Guidline%20Document.docx\r\n\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "66",
        "Question": "How can one apply for start-up incubation at TIIR ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Caution money is a one time refundable amount of Rs.10000 which is taken by the institute in the first semester from all students to cover any and all damages caused by the student to institute property. Caution deposit can only be returned after a student has received degree and graduated from college. A notice will be sent by webmail requesting you to update your Personal Details in your NITRIS portal. On updating with the proper account number, the institute will then deposit the amount after deducting for any losses you might have caused.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "65",
        "Question": "What is caution money? How does it get refunded ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference:  https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2018/09/03/2006-an-nitr-epic-the-mess-review/\r\n Chief Warden / HMC (Hall Management Committee) or HEC (Hall Executive Committee)  \r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Halls",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "64",
        "Question": "Where does one complain about the quality of the food being served at the eateries on the campus ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per its official website (Link: http://icc.nitrkl.ac.in ) Internal complaint cell is a committee which receives and examines internal complaints from the students, staff and faculty of National Institute of Technology Rourkela who have experienced any sort of delinquency towards them by any of their colleagues. \r\nThe roles and responsibilities are as follows:\r\n1.\tTo evaluate and examine the veracity of the complaint received online by students, staff and faculty before proceeding and delivering any Judgement.\r\n2.\tTo evolve a permanent mechanism for the prevention and redressal of complaints and other acts of disturbance at the Institute\r\n3.\tTo ensure smooth and timely delivery of the judgement and make sure that the complaint is handled with sincerity and deliver an impartial and legitimate judgement unaltered and unbiased due to any other factor. \r\n4.\tTo ensure the implementation of the policy in letter and spirit through proper \r\nreporting of the complaints and their follow-up procedures.\r\n5.\tTo follow and implement the rules, regulations and guidelines laid down for redressal of complaint\r\n\r\nOne can easily file an internal complaint by visiting the website of Internal Complaint Committee and filling the complaint form available at http://icc.nitrkl.ac.in . \r\n\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "63",
        "Question": "What is the Internal Complaint Cell? What are its various roles and responsibilities ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The steps are as mentioned below:-\r\n•\tThe procedure for getting NOC for a passport is online. One can go to https://eapplication.nitrkl.ac.in and login with username and password\r\n•\tGo to Academic->Student information->Academic Forms->Apply R1 form\r\n•\t3)One needs to select NOC for passport in form type and give suitable input in purpose\r\n•\t4)After applying one needs to get that approved/recommended from either the Faculty Advisor or the HOD of his/her respective department\r\n•\tIt’ll be usually available after 4-5 Working days\r\n\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "62",
        "Question": "What is the procedure for getting the NOC certificate for a passport ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A student must first provide a valid reason for owning and riding the scooty to the Dean Student Welfare. \r\nUsually, students need to be day scholars or PhD students to be allowed. Students involved in fests can take permission to use a two wheeler for a specific period before the fest.\r\nOnce they are issued a pass, there may be specific guidelines. Such as not entering academic area after 11. Students owning startups in TIIR can own a two wheeler as well after following the necessary procedures. ",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "61",
        "Question": "What are the rules for owning and riding a two-wheeler on campus for astudent ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "To the ICC: Internal Complaint Committee.",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "60",
        "Question": "Where can one report cases of Sexual harassment on campus ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "References: http://nitrkl.ac.in/Institute/Rules/ (8, 10, 11)      \thttp://nitrkl.ac.in/docs/Regulation_Form/Regulation/20092018170904660.pdf (check this - point no. 5)    \thttp://nitrkl.ac.in/docs/Regulation_Form/Regulation/07092018113023398.pdf\r\n\t\r\nForm No. NITR/AC/110 on Institute Website needs to be filled and submitted to apply for medical leave in the case of treatment from a medical centre outside dispensary. The final decision regarding the grant of leave is taken by the Chief Medical Officer on a case by case basis. The process and requirements for the application is included in the links above.\r\n\r\nhttps://photos.app.goo.gl/fUZDp4FvtKHW8bC19",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "59",
        "Question": "Is the medical certificate by a doctor from a private hospital be a valid document for getting leave? Under what circumstances does this happen ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "References:  http://nitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/CurrentStudents/10TrainingPlacement/Default.aspx\r\nhttp://placements.nitrkl.ac.in/\r\n\r\nThe Training and Placement Department of National Institute of Technology, Rourkela, headed by a senior faculty member, manages placement activities and keeps liaison with various industrial groups and research organisations. The department works in close co-ordination with a student placement committee comprising students chosen from various departments. The Training and Placement Cell of the Institute centrally helps in constituting the job carrier for the graduating students of all Departments. Its excellent infrastructure supports each and every stage of the placement processes in arranging pre-placement talks, written test, group discussion, interviews etc.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "58",
        "Question": "What is the role of the Placement Committee in the institute ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The student is expected to first have the income certificate and also, in the case of even semester, proof of payment of waived amount in the last semester(screen shot is enough for online payment).\r\nWith the above mentioned, the student should go to the Assistant Registrar. The student is encouraged to do this quickly before more students come for the same and thus more time has to be wasted by the student to complete the process. In case the student has already paid the excess fee, the fee for the next semester onwards will be compensated.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "57",
        "Question": "How should one deal with a situation wherein the fee they are asked to pay is different as they are supposed to receive a waiver? What are the necessary steps to be taken ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Monday to Saturday - 9:00 am to 11:30 am and 4:00 pm to 7:00 pm\r\nOrdinary Holidays  - 9:00 am to 11:30 am\r\nSundays and National Holidays – Closed\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "56",
        "Question": "What are the timings of the dispensary throughout the week ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per the semester registration notice \r\n(link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1XfS4sPpGYWONcOWXtkVg0d36sBSOsg1_ )\r\nFor DD payment, one must obtain the following document online and print it. The procedure is as mentioned below:-\r\n1. Go to nitrkl.ac.in->Students->Online Fee Payment->Semester Registration Fees\r\n2) Enter NIT Rourkela in the institution name->Roll no and other required fields and click on pay now to initiate the payment\r\n3) Select DD Payment Mode\r\n4) Enter Drawer name, DD date, and DD number and click on submit and Ok to generate challan\r\n5) Students can deposit DD along with generated challan at any ICICI Bank Branched across India  or they can submit at Finance section of NIT Rourkela\r\n6) Please do not change contents on slip manually. ICICI Bank reserves to refuse payment if same is different from content of instruction slip generated from portal\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "55",
        "Question": "What is the procedure for demand draft fee payment ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Freshmen recieve their Nitris Id and Password before the pre registration for first semester. This is done just after orientation for students having joined through JOSAA or DASA and just after admission for spot round students. Webmail Id and Password are generally given to the students in the last weeks of the month of August.\r\nhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1lf3EqLlH3MAjMkJQsrcAzoMOhNz-blau/view?usp=drivesdk - Last year's schedule",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "54",
        "Question": "When do the freshmen receive their NITRIS and Webmail, ID and password ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "One needs to write an application to the Asst. Registrar, then pay for the transcript at the finance section. (Each copy of transcript costs 500 rupees) \r\nThe receipt of the payment must be submitted to the Asst. Registrar and then the transcript is handed over to the student.",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "53",
        "Question": "How can one avail the transcript needed for submission at variousuniversities ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: http://www.nitrkl.ac.in/Academics/TSUs/OAC.aspx\r\n\r\nLocated at the Computer Science and Engineering Department, 1st floor. The Office Automation Cell (OAC) of NIT Rourkela has been established in the year 2008 as a Technical Service Unit to cater the need of software systems for various institutional activities. The cell provides software solutions and maintenance to academic, co-academic, and non-academic processes.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "52",
        "Question": "Where is the Automation cell of the institute is located? What are its functions ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: https://www.google.com/url?q=http://nitrkl.ac.in/oldwebsite/IntraWeb/Academics/Regulation/doc/BTech.pdf&sa=U&ved=0ahUKEwiqppi3gOngAhWViXAKHWGdAWgQFggHMAE&client=internal-uds-cse&cx=013240514921589880003:yzbsbodyxjq&usg=AOvVaw1zPiOzeNmMVpu_bCUH000M\r\n(Point - 6.4b)\r\nFamily calamity: Dean (SW) may sanction leave upto 20 working days in a semester on ground of a family calamity. Death of a parent or sibling, a serious illness (involving a serious heart, brain or kidney disease,\r\nany kind of cancer, or a major operation of a parent) will normally satisfy requirement for sanction of leave.\r\nNote that this applies only in the case where the patient/deceased are your parents, grandparents, or blood related siblings. No other members of the family are included.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "51",
        "Question": "Under what circumstances can a student avail a calamity leave ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Provisional Admission letter \r\nHall Allotment letter\r\n(specifically for first year students)",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Examinations",
            "Halls",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "50",
        "Question": "What are the different documents which act as an ID card in the first semester ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Facebook and instagram are the social media spheres where scp has its presence.\r\nInstagram link: @scp.nitr         Facebook: Student Counselling Program, NIT Rourkela\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "49",
        "Question": "What are the various social media spheres where SCP has it’s presence?Please provide a link to the same ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "In case you want to leave NITR before the completion of your graduation, you must first write a letter addressed to the dean academics requesting for the same, specifying the reason why you want to leave the institute. Thereafter, the letter has to be signed by both your faculty advisor and your Head of Department. The letter then has to be submitted to the Dean, who will give you the clearance form. After submitting it to the Dean’s office, you will be given the leaving certificate which will have everything from Conduct to Migration certificate.\r\nSource : A mentee who has gone through the above process\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "48",
        "Question": "How does one avail a transfer certificate from NIT Rourkela? Please elucidate the steps needed ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "From the SBI branch or the person can apply for R1 form to get the details. ",
        "Category": [
            "Administration"
        ],
        "QNO": "47",
        "Question": "Fee struture details ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Go to Student Information section of NITRIS following which you need to click on \"Apply R1 form\" under \"Academic Forms\" section on Student information page. Select Payment receipt from the drop down list on the page you get redirected to. Choose year and semester and type the purpose and click on Apply. After that, ask your Faculty Advisor to recommend it so that you can collect it from the Academics office the next day.",
        "Category": [
            "Administration"
        ],
        "QNO": "46",
        "Question": "Where does one avail the fee receipt from? And how ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A student has to get a satisfactory grade in his/her respective EAAs in both semesters in order to opt for Minor Degree/ branch change. Getting an unsatisfactory result in either is equivalent to failing in other subjects. Nothing fixed decision has been taken regarding internship and placement but if Unsatisfactory in EAAs is strictly considered as a backlog, then same rules as of other subjects will be applicable for them.\r\n\r\nhttps://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2018/08/06/1901-question-seek-discover-ask-a-question-30",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "45",
        "Question": "What is the significance of Satisfactory and Unsatisfactory grade in PE/NSS/NCC?What role does it play in future scenarios of placements and internship ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A student has to get a satisfactory grade in his/her respective EAAs in both semesters in order to opt for Minor Degree/ branch change. Getting an unsatisfactory result in either is equivalent to failing in other subjects. Nothing fixed decision has been taken on internships and placements. But if getting U in NSS is strictly considered as getting a backlog in other subjects, same rules will be applicable.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "44",
        "Question": "What is the significance of Satisfactory and Unsatisfactory grade in PE/NSS/NCC?What role does it play in future scenarios of placements and internship ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The various R1 forms one can apply for are:\r\n1. Fee Structure\r\n2. Conduct Certificate\r\n3. Course Completion Certificate\r\n4. Grade Card\r\n5. Language Certificate\r\n6. NOC for passport\r\n7. Payment Receipt\r\n8. Studentship Certificate",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "43",
        "Question": "What are the various R1 forms one can apply for ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "http://nitrkl.ac.in/Academics/AcademicProcess/Curricula.aspx",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "30",
        "Question": "Can you provide a link to the updated syllabus of the Undergraduate and Postgraduate courses ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Cases like family disaster or any severe health issues one student can opt for mid sem. For family disaster student need leave application signed by his/her faculty adviser and head of the department also need to get it approved by dean academics. For medical cases, student need medical reference from dispensary. He/ she needs at least 95% attendance in each subject to avoid grade back.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "29",
        "Question": "Under what circumstances can one opt for mid-semester ? What are thedifferent documents required for each situation? How does one ensure he/she doesn’tget a grade back while opting for them ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "One can deregister a maximum of 3 subjects in one semester which can be taken later on as an additional course which is subject to availability of slots. These subjects can be taken in normal semesters only (autumn/spring) and can't be taken as a summer course. No penalty of grade back is levied for the course. \r\nIn case, if no available slots are there in any of the regular semesters then he/she needs to take an additional semester to clear that subject. The normal rules regarding attendance apply if someone takes a deregistered subject. \r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "28",
        "Question": "What are the various rules pertaining to deregistration ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A student gets a backlog in a paper when he fails in that subject.\r\n\r\nA student gets a debar in a paper if he gets less than nearly 75% attendance in that subject(more than 16 absents fro 4 credit course,more than 12 for 3 credit and more than 4 for 2 credit)\r\n\r\nA student can deregister a paper at the beginning of the semester if he wishes to appear for that paper in some other semester.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations"
        ],
        "QNO": "27",
        "Question": "What is the difference between a backlog, debar and deregistration ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "In the case of erratic checking, first the course teacher has to be informed. If he/she fails to address the issue, then approach the Faculty Advisor, the Head of the Department and lastly the Dean Academics if the issue has still not been addressed. If any teacher refuses to show answer scripts for checking, then you have every right to demand for it. For erratic checking, it is a more subjective case.\r\nSource : MM members",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations"
        ],
        "QNO": "26",
        "Question": "Whom does one report to in case of erratic checking? What are the procedures to be followed ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/career/research-internships\r\n\r\nA lot of opportunities are mentioned here with every detail",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments"
        ],
        "QNO": "25",
        "Question": "What are research internships ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "It is after the mid sem results are out that you know that the paper checking is partial and the Professor has a grudge on you according to you.\r\nOne should take the following measures to tackle with this issue:\r\n1. Keep working hard so that the prof doesn't get a chance to deduct more marks.\r\n2. Wait for the end semester results to be out and if you're not satisfied with your grade then you must go to the Prof and ask him to show you your paper once.\r\n3. After going through your paper, if you still think that marks have been deducted deliberately you can approach your Fac-ad once and discuss with him regarding this in a sensible manner and see what he suggests and act accordingly. ",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments"
        ],
        "QNO": "24",
        "Question": "What should a student do in case a faculty is holding a deliberate grudge against him/her ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/2017/08/14/1335-clearing-the-pandemonium-ask-a-question-30/\r\n\r\nFor first-year students, the senate has taken a decision to incorporate branch changes, and this doesn’t apply to the students who are not in first year. A maximum of 5% students from a branch would be allowed to change their branch, subject to vacancies in other branches. But that 5% is a strict 5% or else some branches would become completely vacant. Every student aspires to study in departments like CS and EC but we want to give equal importance to departments like Ceramic, Mining, ID, etc. To apply for branch change, a student must have a CG after first year of 8.5 or above. In case two students have the same CG, the student with the higher SG in second semester will be preferred. The student must not have backlogs in any no credit courses as well like NSS etc.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments"
        ],
        "QNO": "23",
        "Question": "What are the various criterions required for a branch change ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "References:\r\nhttp://www.bipf.org.in/pdf/Prof-Ghanashyam-Das-Scholarship-Scheme-2017.pdf\r\nhttp://www.bipf.org.in/pdf/Prof-Ghanashyam-Das-Scholaship-application-form.pdf\r\n\r\nAll required details are present in the links provided above. This scholarship is applicable only for the students from economically disadvantaged families from Odisha. Other eligibility criteria, method of application and the application form are provided above. The form has to be mailed by 30th October every year to the address mentioned in the above.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "22",
        "Question": "Please furnish details about the Ghanshyam Dash Scholarship for higher education ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "(Information obtained from the Library Help Desk)\r\nThe library currently has no provision for issuing a book without an ID card due to the complete automation of the book issuing procedure. Once the ID card for the freshers are made, they are automatically tagged as the library cards. However, if the fresher is in urgent need of issuing the book, they may approach a senior to use their ID card to issue the book first until he/she receives their own ID card.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "21",
        "Question": "How can freshmen issue a book from the library given he/she does not have an ID card ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: https://www.google.com/url?q=http://nitrkl.ac.in/oldwebsite/IntraWeb/Academics/Regulation/doc/BTech.pdf&sa=U&ved=0ahUKEwiqppi3gOngAhWViXAKHWGdAWgQFggHMAE&client=internal-uds-cse&cx=013240514921589880003:yzbsbodyxjq&usg=AOvVaw1zPiOzeNmMVpu_bCUH000M (Point 5.3)\r\n\r\nA student who does not register on the day announced for the purpose can register within next 10 working days on payment of an additional fee as prescribed by the Institute. Normally no late registration shall be permitted after the tenth working day from the scheduled date, except in special cases like those directed by MHRD or MHRD approved authorities in 1st semester, a serious medical problem, a family calamity or participation in a national event, to be approved by the Director on recommendation of Dean (Academic). However, under no circumstances, even with approved leave, late registration after 45 calendar days from the scheduled date of registration is allowed. A student must repeat the semester in the following year. In case of late registration, all classes between the expected date of registration and the actual date will be considered as absence. The student may, however, apply for leave to Dean (Academic), if admissible under leave rules”. No special allowance may be claimed in the matter of assessment / evaluation or grading.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "20",
        "Question": "Does late registration affect attendance ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "A freshman can change from NCC to NSS/PE within 10 days of the allotment, or in one month in exceptional cases. He/She has to contact the ANO of the NCC (present – Mr. Ajit Behera, Metallurgy department) for the change. They should also physically go to a class of NSS/PE and see that their names are added to the roll call list.\r\nSource : Quoted by SUO (Tapas Nayak)",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "19",
        "Question": "How do a freshmen shift back to NSS/PE given I had opted for NCC willingly ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "http://nss.nitrkl.ac.in/ \r\nThis is the official website of NITR NSS website and the coordinators list can be searched in it for all years. Current NSS co-ordinators list can be found at this link : http://nss.nitrkl.ac.in/team2018-19.php\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "18",
        "Question": "Where can one find the list of coordinators of NSS ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Deregister means a student won’t be able to attend the classes for that subject and cant appear for the exam .he/ she can take that subject in subsequent semesters.\r\nRepercussion - If they are not able to make up for the deregistered subjects, they would eventually require an extra semester.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "17",
        "Question": "What is the meaning of deregistration? When can one take up the theorycourse and lab course next? What are its repercussions ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Senate is the most significant body in campus when it comes to anything related to academics or affects the entire populace of NITR. \r\nIt consists of all the departments HODs, few select Professors, Asst. Registrar and 2-3 student representatives (with at least 1 from both UG and PG). \r\nThey take all decisions regardless academics such as how many credits a course should be of, examination criteria, how many classes to be taken, timings of classes, etc. ",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "16",
        "Question": "What is the Senate? How does it function? What are their roles and responsibilities ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "TYPICAL OFFENCES TO BE CONSIDERED BY ISDC\r\nA. General Offences\r\n1.\tMisbehaving with a student in the hostel.\r\n2.\tMisbehaving with a student in academic area, sports field or other\r\nActivity area\r\n3.\tRiding motorbike without crash helmet, at high speed or with 2\r\npillion riders, parking in hostel area for the 3rd or more time. \r\n4.\tObstructing a student from pursuing his studies peacefully by\r\npersistent disturbance, loud noise etc.\r\n5.\tThrowing trash or spitting on the road, corridors or public places \r\n6.\tSmoking or chewing tobacco in academic area and halls of\r\nresidence, (including roads and open space), canteens, playgrounds\r\nand other public spaces.\r\n7.\tWillfully causing minor damage to buildings, furniture or other\r\nresources.\r\n8.\tMisbehaving with a professor, employee or visitor anywhere, outside\r\nthe class room.\r\n9.\tMisbehaving with a professor, employee or visitor in drunken /\r\nintoxicated state outside the class room. \r\n10.\tMaking unauthorized statements before print or electronic media on\r\nmatters related to institute administration.\r\n11.\tDamaging Institute property in a drunken / intoxicated state. \r\n12.\tEntering an outside water body, roof top or any location understood\r\nto be out of bounds to students for maintaining safety and security.\r\n13.\tStealing private or public property. \r\n14.\tMisusing an elected office in SAC or HAC for personal gain. \r\n15.\tTampering I-card, Medical card or another identity given by the\r\nInstitute.\r\n16.\tConsciously not reporting an offence to authorities or withholding\r\ninformation from an enquiry office.\r\n17.\tForgery, impersonation and other ways of using the identity of\r\nanother student.\r\n18.\tWillingly damaging, defacing or destroying a building, furniture, \r\nequipment, book or other property owned or controlled by the\r\n19.\tInstitute or otherwise located within the precincts of the Institute\r\n20.\tSmoking in class, laboratory, library, seminar halls or auditorium.\r\n21.\tPhysically obstructing a faculty or staff member from performing his\r\nduty.\r\n22.\tSystematically harassing another student \r\n23.\tHarassing female students through verbal abuse or written abuse.\r\n24.\tParticipating in a group (3 or more students) to quarrel with or to\r\nintimidate another student or an outsider.\r\n25.\tParticipating in a group (3 or more students) to quarrel with or to\r\nintimidate another group of students \r\n26.\tThreatening, abusing or assaulting an institute staff including\r\ncontract labour.  Stealing Institute property (e.g. computer parts).\r\n27.\tCreating division among students on the basis of religion, caste,\r\nhome state or any other criteria \r\n28.\tImpersonating or signing for a faculty or employee of the institute or\r\nproducing a forged document; taking over function of an Institute\r\nstaff or officer without authority.\r\n29.\tLying or showing disrespect to Standing Disciplinary Committee or\r\nanother enquiry committee. \r\n30.\tSexual harassment of a fellow student or of another person. [“sexual\r\nharassment” means any unwanted sexual attention, in the form of\r\nphysical contact, comments, inappropriate gestures, suggestions,\r\nhints, innuendo or similar conduct which the perpetrator knows, or\r\nought reasonably to know, will create an environment in which the\r\nperson subject to the conduct is humiliated or denied his or her\r\ndignity.]\r\n\r\n31.\tInterfering with a disciplinary proceeding by bribing, threatening or\r\nintimidating a witness or any other person related to a disciplinary\r\ncase\r\n32.\tFighting with a student or outsider leading to physical injury. \r\n33.\tAssaulting and injuring another student without sufficient fight back.\r\n34.\tEntering Swimming Pool or similarly barricaded area without\r\nauthority seriously compromising safety and security of self and\r\nothers\r\n35.\tThreatening, abusing or assaulting a faculty member or academic\r\nofficer. \r\n36.\tLeading a group (3 or more students) to quarrel with or to intimidate\r\nanother group of students \r\n37.\tLeading a group (3 or more students) to quarrel with or to intimidate\r\nan outsider, whatever the cause \r\n38.\tUsing motor vehicle (2 or 4 wheeler) to intimidate a student or\r\nemployee of the institute.\r\n39.\tHarassing female students through photographic, print or electronic\r\nmedia \r\n40.\tParticipating in a group fight leading to physical injury \r\n41.\tOrganising or leading a scuffle, fight or abusive quarrel between\r\ngroups of students in or around a student function. \r\n42.\tPossessing or using hallucinogenic drug \r\n43.\tLeading a group fight leading to physical injury \r\n44.\tUnauthorized entry into a professor‟s room, laboratory, library or\r\nsimilar place e.g. by using a duplicate key, breaking a lock or by any\r\nother means\r\n45.\tInteracting with persons or groups believing in violence \r\n46.\tSupplying or selling hallucinogenic drug \r\n47.\tPossessing explosives, firearms or such dangerous items Activities prejudicial to national security or communal harmony\r\nB. Offences related to harassment of freshers [ For Senior Students]\r\n1.\tCalling First Year student to meet anywhere in campus or outside \r\n2.\tMaking phone calls, handing over used books, offering to show the\r\nmarket to First Year students \r\n3.\tMeeting First Year students in a place where one of them does not\r\nhave a reason to be present at that time\r\n4.\tCalling a first year student to a senior hall or room \r\n5.\tUsing abusive language, asking names in impolite language or similar\r\nthreats\r\n6.\tEntering a First Year Hall without permission of Warden or exceeding\r\nany other permitted limits \r\n7.\tOrganizing or participating in regimented activity such as walking with\r\nface down, wearing clothing of prescribed design or other modes of\r\nsubjugation\r\n8.\tSlapping or beating a fresher or inflicting another physical/mental\r\ntorture on one or more students \r\n9.\tParticipating in a group of seniors inflicting physical or mental torture\r\non freshers \r\n10.\tLeading a group of seniors in a ragging activity \r\nC. Offences related to harassment of freshers [ For Freshers]\r\n1.\tServing as a conduit for passing on ragging-related message or\r\nmaterials from senior students to first year students \r\n2.\tFirst year student using abusive language to senior students or\r\nother first year students\r\nD. Academic Offences\r\n1.\tCreating disturbance in class, library, laboratory or seminar etc. \r\n2.\tMisbehaving with a professor in a class, laboratory, library etc. \r\n3.\tEntering a class, laboratory, library, seminar or similar place in an\r\ninebriated state.\r\n4.\tStealing, damaging or removing pages from library books and other\r\nlibrary material.\r\n5.\tSubmission of the same piece of one‟s own work for assessment\r\nand award of credit in two (or more) instances.\r\n6.\tConsciously placing material from other sources in theses and\r\npublications without acknowledging the author.\r\n7.\tPublishing (or otherwise claiming to be one‟s own) a work without\r\nconsent of other researchers including one‟s research guide.\r\n8.\tManipulating attendance or other ordinary academic record by\r\nelectronic or physical means.\r\n9.\tPresenting a substantial volume of another person‟s work as one‟s\r\nown in a thesis or publication.\r\n10.\tManipulating grades and vital academic records through electronic\r\nor physical means.\r\nE. Examination Related Offences\r\n1.\tCreating disturbance in an examination hall \r\n2.\tMisbehaving with a classmate in examination hall\r\n3.\tPossession of a mobile phone or similar communication device in\r\nactive state in an examination.\r\n4.\tWriting formulas or material on a question paper that can help a\r\nfellow student during examination.\r\n5.\tTalking to another examinee or an outsider during examination.\r\n6.\tWriting on desk in examination hall\r\n7.\tAllowing another student to copy from one‟s answer script \r\n8.\tMisbehaving with a professor in an examination hall \r\n9.\tConsulting a paper, book or a person in corridor, toilet or another\r\nplace. \r\n10.\tPossession of a chit with relevant material in an examination.\r\n11.\tCarrying relevant material by writing on one‟s body (palms, legs etc)\r\nor clothing to examination.\r\n12.\tPossession of a book or significant quantity of written material in\r\nexamination hall.\r\n13.\tCopying from examination script of another candidate\r\n14.\tGoing outside examination area (i.e. outside hall, toilet and\r\nconnecting passage) for any purpose.\r\n15.\tSending question paper or answer script outside examination hall\r\n16.\tSubmitting answer script with answers written outside the hall.\r\n17.\tThreatening an invigilator or a teacher\r\n18.\tImpersonating another candidate in examination of allowing oneself\r\nto be impersonated\r\n19.\tDeliberately acquiring advance knowledge of detailed content of an\r\nexamination paper.\r\n20.\tLarge scale, organized activity for influencing examination process,\r\ngrades or academic records.\r\nF. Offences Related to Public Functions\r\n1.\tCreating disturbance in a student function.\r\n2.\tIndecent behavior in a public function.\r\n3.\tEntering a student function in an inebriated state.\r\n4.\tIndecent behavior in a public function under influence of alcohol or\r\nanother drug.\r\n5.\tViolating barricades in an institute function without sufficient reason or\r\nauthority.\r\n6.\tLeading a disturbance in a student function through organizing\r\nboycott, protest or any other means.\r\n7.\tCreating a group disturbance (violent or otherwise) in a student\r\n8.\tfunction. \r\nG. Cyber Offences\r\n1.\tTampering with one‟s own electronic identification system normally\r\nemployed for giving access or attendance.\r\n2.\tPlacing indecent material or any material likely to disturb harmony\r\nwithin the Institute in NITRKL or other website. \r\n3.\tGaining access into the personal computer of another student and\r\naltering content without the owner‟s consent. \r\n4.\tGaining access into the computer account of another student in a\r\ndepartmental or central computer.\r\n5.\tHarassing a fellow student by using electronic media [SMS, Email,\r\nWeb site] \r\n6.\tStealing or otherwise possessing electronic password of a faculty,\r\n7.\tstaff member or an outsider related to the institute without latter‟s\r\nconsent.\r\n8.\tPassing on electronic password of a faculty or staff member, or an\r\nofficial password to a third person without the consent of the owner \r\n9.\tGaining access and using the personal computer of a faculty or staff\r\nmember or his account in a departmental or central computer by\r\nstealing his password or by other means.\r\n10.\tHarassing or publicly humiliating a female student or another female\r\n11.\tindividual by circulating of objectionable material over electronic\r\nmedia.\r\n12.\tUsing a computer (own account or that of another individual) for doing\r\nserious mischief or for personal gain.\r\n13.\tGaining access into administrative account of a departmental or\r\ncentral computer system, or to any official user account without\r\nauthority, irrespective of the motive.\r\nPINISHMENT FOR MALPRACTICE IN EXAM:\r\n1.\tDeduction of marks by noting on answer script (Up to 10 marks) [ In examination hall\r\nonly]\r\n2.\tAwarding F grade in one paper [ For examination related offences only ].\r\n3.\tAwarding F grade in two or more papers. [ For examination related offences only ].\r\n4.\tAwarding F grade in all theory papers of a semester [ For examination related\r\n5.\toffences only ].\r\n6.\tConversion of grade in one to three courses to „UR‟, thus forcing the student to slow\r\npace.\r\n7.\tAward of „UR‟ status to all courses of 1 semester forcing repeat of the semester or\r\n8.\tgoing to slow pace.\r\n9.\tAward of „UR‟ status to all courses of 2 semesters forcing repeat of whole year.\r\n10.\tAward of „UR‟ status in all courses of a semester or more and mention of “Bad\r\n11.\tConduct” in Conduct Certificate.\r\n12.\tOutright expulsion from the Institute.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "15",
        "Question": "What are the different cases which lead to an ISDC? What is the punishmentfor getting involved in malpractice during the semester examinations ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Heads of institutes like SAC, dispensary, T&P, respective departments can approve leave for a student. Student need to submit his/her leave application signed by faculty adviser, head of the department and dean of academics. For how many days a student would get leave that depends.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "14",
        "Question": "What are the various heads under which students are granted leave? Pleaseprovide comprehensive details about the pre-requisites, a number of days the leave isawarded and also how does ensure that the leave is granted ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Qualifying degree certificate is an official document given to the qualifying students provided by the universities after the successful completion of the course awarding you with a valid degree",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "13",
        "Question": "Whats a Qualifying Degree Certificate? Please note this certificate is asked foreven after submitting one’s high school certificate (12th Standard Passing certificate) ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per the Monday Morning article \r\n(Link: https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2018/01/08/1612-delineating-the-dilemmas-ask-a-question-120/ )\r\nQuoting Dean Academics, Prof. K.K. Mahapatra who answered a similar question “No, there is no such system. It might be needed specifically for a particular student for some specific journal, but that’s not the general case. As per my knowledge, the students along with their supervisors can publish their publications and there has not been any hassle so far. Usually, if a student is taking help from a particular organization or getting sponsorship only then, in that case, it is their moral responsibility to mention the name of that organization in the acknowledgment section stating that they could successfully complete the publication because of the help of that organization. However, if this question is exclusively meant for a specific student and that has to be treated individually.” \r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "12",
        "Question": "Is there any bound agreement signed by Ph.D. scholars for authorship before working on a project? Does the institute advise its researchers & PI's to go through the ICMJE protocol of publishing and follow points and methods of assignment of Authors? Who checks it ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per the official website of All India Council for Technological Education(Link: https://www.aicte-india.org/bureaus/rifd/teqip ) TEQIP is defined as Technical Education Quality Improvement Programme of Government of India (TEQIP) which is being implemented as a World Bank assisted project to improve the quality of technical education system in the country.\r\n\r\nNIT Rourkela is a TEQIP-III (phase-III) institute for which the objectives are mentioned in (Link: http://www.teqip.in/objective.html) \r\n\r\nAs per the documents available in institute website \r\n(Link: http://nitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/Institute/TEQIP/Default.aspx ) and the document (Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=17rGFX5CHzebL703oTp7YdPgXfCWpDFlu )\r\n\r\nMany opportunities which the students can avail includes conducting courses and soft skills training for academically weak students. Special summer semester programmes are conducted for students securing fail grades following spring semester examinations. This enables students to complete the courses in which they secure fail grade. The summer course is for 6 week duration and makes a new assessment for weak students based on their performance in summer course. Special programs are also conducted in pre-final years in order to improve and horn their technical and soft skills. Normally 6-8 sessions are conducted during pre-final year and 2-3 sessions are conducted in final year. These sessions are normally conducted in the weekends. Classes are taken by selected experienced faculty and external experts. More details are available at \r\n(Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=17rGFX5CHzebL703oTp7YdPgXfCWpDFlu ). Information regarding the same are shared via the institute webmail and interested students can take part in it.\r\n\r\nThe various schemes and opportunities under this are:-\r\n\r\n•\tExchanging of faculty and students between universities.\r\n•\tStarting of specialized Master’s program for industries, where junior level executives will be imparted PG programmes.\r\n•\tJoint programs of research and development activities.\r\n•\tExposure of students to state of art technology through up-gradation of laboratories.\r\n\tQuantitatively increasing and qualitatively improving research by their faculty individually, jointly and collaboratively which includes\r\n•\tFormation of research groups within Departments.\r\n•\tInduction of new faculty who are fresh from active research into the groups.\r\n•\tIncentive and recognition of research outcomes in terms of future promotion\r\n\tDeveloping research interest among undergraduate students, and Reorienting Summer Internship and Research Experience\r\n•\tTaking up industry oriented project work and experimental work during the final year project.\r\n•\tIncreasing the credit and time period of project work during final year.\r\n•\tGold medal for best B.Tech project during every Annual Convocation.\r\n\tCollaborating with Indian and foreign institutions in academic and research area through MoUs. The steps taken/ to be taken in this regard are\r\n•\tIncentives in terms of funds availability and recognition of merit / promotion.\r\n•\tEncouragement to secure industry and Govt. sponsored projects.\r\n•\tAvailability of global resources through on-line library.\r\n\r\nMore details available at \r\n(Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=17rGFX5CHzebL703oTp7YdPgXfCWpDFlu ).\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "11",
        "Question": "What is TEQIP? How can students avail its benefits? What are the various schemes and opportunities under it ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per the Academic Regulations \r\n(Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1le3h9A7CZcCAGScwAxRrMxrKJD5Kfmq1 ) the main features are as follows:-\r\n\r\n•\tThe duration of the course leading to B.Tech. Degree will ordinarily be four years. A student may, however, opt for the slow pace programme if he does not feel comfortable with the work load. Under certain cases, e.g., poor grades, he is required to proceed in slow pace to minimize the time required to complete the programme. If a student gets a CGPA less than 6.00 in three consecutive semesters, he must leave the Institute. Therefore, it is in a student’s interest to estimate his own capability and register under a slow pace mode from third semester onwards, or even from the First semester. The criterion for slow pace is:\r\n\r\n•\tIt is necessary for a student to maintain a CGPA equal to or above 6.00 at all times. If the CGPA falls below 6.00 he should enter a slow pace programme in his own interest. The following procedure will be used to make “slow pace” mandatory for a student with poor performance. A modified grade point average called MGPA will be computed by replacing all F and X grades by P grades. If the MGPA equals or exceeds 6.00, he may be permitted to register for a full suite of higher semester courses at the discretion of Faculty Advisor. If the MGPA remains below 6.00 the student must enter a slow pace programme. To register in higher semester in slow pace, the number of courses being decided by Faculty Advisor. To leave the Institute if CGPA falls below 6.00 in three consecutive semesters.\r\n\r\n•\tYear back means the student has to get readmitted to the corresponding year and repeat the academic courses again and the criterion is as follows :\r\n\r\n•\tIn case of a First Year student, if the CGPA is between 5.00 and 5.69, he will re-register in the First Semester and start the programme afresh. The CGPA in the repeat year must exceed 6.00, else the student has to leave the Institute.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "10",
        "Question": "Please elucidate the difference between slow pace and year back and what are the criterions related to them ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "As per the Academic Regulations \r\n(Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1le3h9A7CZcCAGScwAxRrMxrKJD5Kfmq1 ) and \r\nDisciplinary manual\r\n(Link: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1Ya5MpIJbAnXZ-sZK-X5UCg-0en03X13z )\r\nOne student must leave if:\r\n\r\n•\tIf a student gets a CGPA less than 6.00 in three consecutive semesters, he must leave the Institute.\r\n•\tAfter first year if the CGPA < 5.00\r\n•\tAs per the clause P-24 and P-25 of disciplinary manual, outright expulsion from the institute can also be a step under certain circumstances\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "9",
        "Question": "What are the circumstances under which a student is shown the door and asked to leave the campus ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "When a student is appearing for summer the number of absents which is allowed in a regular semester that reduced to half.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments",
            "Examinations"
        ],
        "QNO": "8",
        "Question": "What are the drawbacks of opting for a course in summer ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "There is no publicly viewable list of faculty advisors. For the students who have registered in time and have taken part in the orientation process, they will be taken to their faculty advisors personally by the HoD. For those who have registered late, they can find out who the faculty advisor for their batch is by asking in the office of their department. Once ID card is issued, your faculty advisor details are printed on it.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Administration",
            "Departments"
        ],
        "QNO": "7",
        "Question": "How does one find out about the faculty advisors of various departments, especially when one has not been issued an ID card in the initial month of the opening of session ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "TA marks are 20 marks out of total 100 marks per subject which are completely left the professors. Marks can be given basing on the assignments, class tests, attendance, tutorial and classroom performances etc. As it is completely left to the professors there is no way there will be an uniformity in marking. Generally these marks  are awarded on the basis of a teacher's impression of a student, so it's important to be in good books of the teacher to get good TA marks.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "6",
        "Question": "How do you explain the concept of Teachers Assesment to a freshman ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Backlog is described as that scenario when a student fails a particular subject because of poor performance. The student must then repeat the subject either in the following summer (with no grade back) or take up the course next year with his/her juniors (with a grade back i.e the max grade he would be securing would be A)\r\nDebar is described as that scenario when a student gets removed from the course due to attendance or any other personal issue. He/she then has to repeat the course in any other semester and also need not attend classes in that semester.\r\nDeregister is described by that scenario where he/she simply removes his registration from that course and pursues it in a later semester. The SGPA/CGPA won’t be affected in any way because the student would anyway complete the course before graduating at some point of time.\r\nGrade back is defined as that scenario when the student gets his/her grade subtracted by one level before even appearing for it. The possible reasons maybe attendance. If he/she fails to maintain the min 75% for a course in a semester (Max 8 absents for 4 credit courses,  6 absents for 3 credit courses and 4 absents for 2 credit courses), he/she would then get a grade back. So the max possible grade which can be secured would be A and not EX.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "5",
        "Question": "How does a backlog, debar, de-registration and grade back affect one's SGPA and CGPA as a whole ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: http://nitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/Prospective_Students/11FAQs/Default.aspx (D8)\r\n\r\nSince Percentage is a point estimation and CGPA in an interval estimation, NIT Rourkela does not prescribe any conversion formula to convert CGPA to Percentage. However, for reference one can use the formula: Percentage = (CGPA – 0.5) x 10.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "General Awareness",
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "42",
        "Question": "What is the CGPA to % criteria at our institute ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "8.0 CGPA is the cutoff to qualify for honours degree. Every person above 8.0 CG gets a honours degree.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "4",
        "Question": "Under what circumstances is honours degree awarded to a graduate ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "No they cannot apply for minor degree.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "3",
        "Question": "Can people with NSS/ PE/NCC backlog apply for minor degree courses ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Enrolling in spot round won't lead to\r\n getting absent in the previous classes in which one was not there on campus. Instead that will get displayed as late registration on NITRIS marked by pink colour. But if such an error happens,the student should contact his Faculty Advisor first and then take any step accordingly to resolve this issue.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "2",
        "Question": "Does enrolling in Spot Round lead to getting absent in the previous classes in which one was not there on campus? How does rectify an error, if any ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Go to Academics section on NITR's official website. Select \"Academic Forms\" option on the extreme left and click on \" AC-R-02\r\nForm for ID card\" to download the form for a new ID card. Fill the form and get the necessary signatures and submit that at the Academics office and pay INR 500 there by means of debit card or challan. You can collect your new ID card after a few days from the office.  \r\n\r\nwww.nitrkl.ac.in/docs/AcademicForms/16032017163512052.pdf",
        "Category": [
            "Academics"
        ],
        "QNO": "1",
        "Question": "How can one apply for a new ID card after he/she has lost one ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The Pendyala Vijaylakshmi Memorial endows two scholarships: Pendyala Anasuya Memorial Scholarship and Pendyala Vijaylakshmi Memorial Scholarship. Monetary Aid given is Rs.40,000 per semester. The eligibility criteria can be accessed from the first link provided below. The two scholarships have slightly different eligibility criteria. The application form is to be submitted to the Asst. Registrar office.\r\nReferences: http://nitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/FacultyStaff/docs/181501331055_1.pdf\t\t     http://www.nitrkl.ac.in/docs/Announcement/17082018131300082.pdf\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "General Awareness",
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "40",
        "Question": "What are the different scholarships endowed by the Pendayala Vijaylakshmi Memorial? What is the monetary aid given? Who are eligible for this? What are the different eligible criterions for the same? Where does one submit the application form ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "• Students can check their seating arrangement for the Mid-semester exam (Spring 2018-19) in their respective NITRIS portal \r\n• Id card is a must for appearing in the examination.Any one who has lost his/her Id card may apply for a duplicate Id card(in  prescribed form R-02 with fee receipt) by an announced date.\r\n•Students appearing the exams should be present in the exam hall at least 10 mins before the starting of the examination. Late comers may not be  allowed to appear the exam unless permitted otherwise by the competent authority.\r\n• Sleep properly and don’t stress out. In case of loss of ID card, inform Exam Control Room (LA 101) about the same. In case of inability to write exam due to health issues, go to dispensary and inform them the same. You can apply for taking the exam later only with the suitable medical certificate from dispensary.\r\n•Mobile phones are strictly prohibited inside the exam hall.  If any student is caught inside the exam hall with mobiles, then strict action will be taken against him/her.",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness",
            "Halls"
        ],
        "QNO": "39",
        "Question": "What are some of the tips one would give a freshman before attending their first mid-semester examination ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2018/03/26/1789-extending-a-hand-the-student-counselling-programme-review/\r\n\r\nIt was observed that the first and second-year students were often stressed about the curriculum and examinations and we observed that some particular subjects have a very high failure rate. The students did not feel comfortable to ask the teachers and the teachers also did not get the viewpoint of students at times. Thus, it was decided that tutors from 2nd year, 3rd Year and subsequent year students could be appointed to aide the students. The tutors were remunerated with Rs 500 per class.\r\nA link will be sent in an announcement through Webmail for applying for remedials. At the same time, the same link will be circulated by WhatsApp to first years by their respective mentors.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness",
            "Student Counselling Programme"
        ],
        "QNO": "38",
        "Question": "How are remedial classes helpful for a mentee? How can he/she enroll in one ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference : https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2019/02/11/2282-part-2-the-major-minor-fiasco/\r\n\r\nYes. For the 2017-21 batch, the grade scored in a course in the minor degree is considered to be the same as for a major degree and is taken into account for the calculation of CGPA. It is a part of your grade card.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "37",
        "Question": "Will the grade in minor degree affect one’s CGPA ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "Reference: https://www.google.com/url?q=http://nitrkl.ac.in/oldwebsite/IntraWeb/Academics/Regulation/doc/BTech.pdf&sa=U&ved=0ahUKEwiqppi3gOngAhWViXAKHWGdAWgQFggHMAE&client=internal-uds-cse&cx=013240514921589880003:yzbsbodyxjq&usg=AOvVaw1zPiOzeNmMVpu_bCUH000M (Page - 16)\r\n \r\nA = Number of unauthorized absences\r\n S = Sittings per week (1 hr. for lecture and tutorial as well as 3 hrs.lab classes) for a subject in a normal semester  and define separately for regular sem and summer quarter\r\n Algorithm for computation of Grade Back and X Grade :\r\nIf (A <= 2 * S) then no penalty\r\nIf (A > 2 * S and A <= 4 * S) then Grade back by one step\r\nIf (A > 4 * S) then X grade\r\nIf (TA > 6 * S) then X grade\r\nFor a more easier approach, student can access the information from their NITRIS portal by going to Attendance & Leave>Class Attendance & Leave. There is a table there explaining the penalty for absence in class for various courses.\r\n\r\nhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1-v0AC3qlKbXxiOoicpBtAif4MOnLYHQp/view?usp=sharing\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Examinations",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "36",
        "Question": "How does one understand how much absent leads to grade back in a particular course ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "According to the new curriculum as per the report mentioned in Monday morning \r\n(Link: https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/article/2019/02/11/2290-part-3-redefining-nit-rs-pedagogy-curriculum-review-meeting/ )\r\n\r\nThe new curriculum is defined in such a way that it benefits the students of NITR and helps their overall growth. Students are encouraged more now to carry out research work and the research project has been made mandatory including credits for it. Earlier, it had an option of a research project or a course. Also, as per the changes in curriculum, many branches including but not limited to Life Science etc. will be such that subjects will be shuffled and the necessary ones required for pursuing interdisciplinary research in the field of Life Sciences would be retained.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "35",
        "Question": "Is one allowed to do interdepartmental research projects under the new curriculum ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "The 5 minute gaps between the classes are not followed and most of the professors tend to utilize it. Even after an official notice about the change of timings and reducing the official timing of a class from 60 mins each to 55 mins for class each(excluding labs which run for more than 1 hour) so that enough time between the classes can be given for the students to commence and settle. However most of the classes are scheduled back to back and most of them are in one classroom only (only some classes like OE etc. are required to change classes) and because of this, the professors continue teaching till the arrival of the next professor.\r\n\r\nThe discrepancy in above issue can be brought into the notice of authorities by reporting it to the Assistant Registrar or Dean Academics who can take suitable and necessary steps regarding the same. \r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "34",
        "Question": "Is the 5 minute gaps between classes followed? Whom does a student contact to report about the discrepancy in the above matter ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "For the students having minor degree in computer science, they are only eligible for the placement for the respective CS company if either the company had stated the policy for recruitment of individuals having the minor degrees or the HRs of the recruiting company are convinced by the placement coordinators to do the same. Thus, for on campus placements, it depends on if the HR has been convinced by the placement committee or not whereas for off campus placement, it depends on the specific recruitment policy of the PSU. Currently, PSUs hiring CS graduates aren't generally recruiting them(referring to the minor degree graduates). But having minor in CS is an additional remark for the individuals getting placements in the company that are open for all branches and non-core companies, like analytics.\r\nSource : Quoted by multiple PCs\r\nhttps://qualifygate.com/psu-recruitment-through-gate-cse/",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness",
            "Miscellaneous"
        ],
        "QNO": "33",
        "Question": "Can one take up a government job on the basis of the minor degree opted for at NIT Rourkela? That is, can a 119BMXXYY who opted for a CS Minor degree, be eligible for a job at PSU which hires CS engineers ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "No. A student from a dual degree program can never change to a single degree program on any basis.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "32",
        "Question": "Can one change into a single degree program from a dual degree program after 1st year on the basis of a good CGPA ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "References: https://mondaymorning.nitrkl.ac.in/2018/08/06/1914-minor-degrees-a-mixed-blessing/\r\n\r\nMeritorious students who have secured CGPA of 7.50 or more (without any backlog) at the end of first year are eligible to opt for minor degree, of their choice, subject to following conditions:\r\nA minor degree can be given in Engineering, Science or Humanities discipline for B.Tech, B.Tech and M.tech Dual degree, Int. M.Sc. and B.Arch students of academic year 2017-18 onwards.\r\nMinor degree will be allocated on completion of 2nd semester, based on CGPA. The minimum CGPA of 7.50 will be considered eligible for registration for minor degree.\r\nA student will be eligible to receive minor degree when he/she takes at least 6 additional courses offered by the department (semester-wise) constituting of minimum 18 credits between 3rd to 8th semesters.\r\nMinor degree credit requirement is over and above the minimum requirements.\r\nThe branch opted for minor degree by a student is a one-time choice and cannot be altered under any circumstances.\r\nNo equivalent courses from other departments can be taken for fulfilling the minimum credit requirement for obtaining Minor degree.\r\nAny student who wishes to leave the Minor degree in between, he/she may be allowed to do so with the permission of Dean (Ac.). His grade-sheet will only reflect the cleared courses.\r\nIf a student fails to complete a Minor degree course within his normal duration, he has the option to either drop the minor degree or he may stay extra semester or year as applicable to complete the same for award of Minor degree.\r\nIn case of a tie in CGPA for allotting Minor Degree, the SGPA of the 2nd semester will be considered.\r\nIn case of CGPA falling below 7.50 after registration, registration will be cancelled\r\n(nitris -> Student Information -> Minor degree choice )\r\nNote that having a backlog in even NSS/PE/NCC will disqualify you from applying for minor. Also note that the grade will be shown in your normal major degree grade sheet.\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "Departments",
            "General Awareness"
        ],
        "QNO": "31",
        "Question": "What are the intricacies of the Minor system introduced at NIT Rourkela, two years back ?"
    },
    {
        "Answer": "References: http://nitrkl.ac.in/OldWebsite/Prospective_Students/11FAQs/Default.aspx\r\n        \t\t   https://scholarships.gov.in/\r\n                             https://www.buddy4study.com/article/sc-st-obc-scholarship\r\n        \t               https://www.buddy4study.com/article/top-government-scholarships\r\nAll state governments provide Post Matriculation Scholarships(PMS) for eligible students of SC/ST category.There are also multiple central level scholarships provided by various departments. The eligibility criteria is different for the scholarships provided by different departments. However, all of these are available at the Home Page of National Scholarship Portal (second link provided above). More information about the various scholarships can be obtained from the third and fourth links. \r\nApplying procedures for Scholarship Schemes for both Fresh and Renewal under NSP are given below:\r\nFresh: Student have to Click on the option “Student Login”, on the home page of National Scholarships Portal. Fill up the application as per the instructions given by the system then click on save button. After saving, student will get a “Temporary ID”. The system will instruct the applicant to submit his/her Temporary ID and date of birth to fill subsequent details. Once registration is complete click on submit button, a Permanent Registration ID is generated which can be used for Renewal and tracking the status of application\r\nRenewal: Renewal Students have to apply with their Application Id and Date of Birth which they registered previous year. Student can also use Forgot Application ID to retrieve their ID. Only those students would be able to Renew who had actually got the scholarships payments last year from NSP.\r\nThe form after filling should be submitted in the Finance and Accounts office(under the Assistant Registrar office).\r\n\r\n",
        "Category": [
            "Academics",
            "General Awareness",
            "Scholarships"
        ],
        "QNO": "41",
        "Question": "What are the various scholarships for SC/ST from states other than Odisha? Please mention the eligibility criteria and procedure to apply for the same ?"
    }
]